Nick Peihl

Full stack software engineer

About

Remote US

□ nickpeihl@gmail.com

(760) 883-0534

npeihl.com

nickpeihl

in nickpeihl

Web App Development

TypeScript Node.js React Redux RxJS

DevOps

Docker Terraform Helm Kubernetes Google Cloud Platform Varnish

Database

Elasticsearch
PostgreSQL
Microsoft SQL Server
ArcSDE

GIS

ArcGIS Desktop / Server Spatial analysis GDAL / OGR

Python

ArcPy Django Jupyter Pandas Geopandas

Summary

I am a full stack engineer with 10+ years experience developing, implementing, and maintaining web applications on every layer including customer requirements, database schemas, DevOps, backend APIs, and frontend components. I work with stakeholders to guide projects from concept to completion.

Experience

Elastic 03/2018 - Present

Principal Software Engineer

Elastic is the company behind the Elastic Stack consisting of Elasticsearch, Kibana, Logstash, and Beats.

- Design, deploy, scale, and maintain the Elastic Maps Service for customers using Bash, PostgreSQL, Varnish, Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform, and Helm.
- Develop, test, and maintain features for the Maps and Dashboards plugins in Kibana using TypeScript, Node.js, Jest, React, Redux, and RxJS.
- Led the production and release of Elastic Maps Server, a new standalone map service product, for enterprise customers by collaborating with Legal, Product Management, Release engineering, and Cloud engineering teams.
- Refactored map service and map data generation saving at least \$42,000 per annum.

San Juan County

06/2013 - 02/2018

GIS Coordinator

- Built fast and responsive geospatial web applications using progressive web app technologies.
- Supervised all GIS department projects and staff.
- Backup IT Manager for supervision of staff and critical decision-making.
- Created Footprint Review a crowdsourcing web application for conflating GIS data.
- Re-negotiated an aerial photography contract to provide higher resolution imagery at no additional cost.

Coachella Valley Association of Governments

08/2005 - 05/2013

GIS Analyst

The Coachella Valley Association of Governments (CVAG) is a municipal planning agency which administers the Coachella Valley Multiple Species Habitat Conservation Plan (CVMSHCP). The CVMSHCP is a 1.1 million acre plan to protect species habitats and ecologies.

- Designed and maintained enterprise geodatabases running on Microsoft SQL Server and PostgreSQL/PostGIS to link geospatial data with a document management system.
- Conducted spatial analyses to determine where and how proposed developments affect protected species habitats and natural communities.
- Designed annual reports showing habitat conservation progress using spatial SOL queries.
- Used Django framework to develop a data entry web application for consultants.

Education

North Dakota State University

Bachelor of Science Management Information Systems / Computer Science